<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on OliverFlecke</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/</link><description>Recent content in Home on OliverFlecke</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://oliverflecke.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Convertible Currency</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/currency/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oliverflecke.me/currency/</guid><description>A minimalistic currency conversion app, available on iPhone, iPad, Apple Watch and Mac! Features Convert between multiple currencies at the same time Support for 180+ different currencies, including popular crypto currencies Offline support allows you to perform conversions even when you are without internet Choose and sort which your currencies Sync your settings and currencies accross your devices Convert currencies directly from your Apple Watch Privacy This application does not access or store any kind of personal data.</description></item><item><title>Authenticate with Github on a Single-Page Application</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/post/github_auth_with_spa/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oliverflecke.me/post/github_auth_with_spa/</guid><description>Introduction For a recent project, I wanted a way to authenticate users, but without all the struggle of managing users and their data. This was for a frontend, single-page application (SPA) where everything could be served as static HTML/CSS/JS files. My solution was to allow users to sign in with their Github credentials using OAuth. This is the best of both worlds: I won&amp;rsquo;t have to store any user data or think much about security, and users don&amp;rsquo;t have to trust me with their email or password.</description></item><item><title>Balut web app</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/post/balut_game/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oliverflecke.me/post/balut_game/</guid><description>Last year when it became impossible to meet up and play games together, I wrote a web implementation of the game Balut. It is not the most known game in the world, but one that I have always enjoyed as a child. The game can be found at balut.app.
Rules of Balut The goal of the game is similar to the game of Yahtzee. The player starts each round with fives dices, and has up to three throws to collect a set of dices that they enter onto the board.</description></item><item><title>Sudoku solver in Prolog</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/post/prolog_sudoku_solver/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oliverflecke.me/post/prolog_sudoku_solver/</guid><description>Primer A few days ago, I was doing a Sudoku, a puzzle game similar to cross word puzzles, but where the goal is to fill out every cell with a number. Each number has to fulfill the following rules:
Each row of numbers must be distinct Each column of numbers must be distinct Each 3x3 square of numbers must be distinct Quite simple, but it can still provide some interesting and challenging problems.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://oliverflecke.me/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://oliverflecke.me/about/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m Oliver Fleckenstein. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer developing web, mobile, and embedded applications. Passionate about technology and building software to solve problems. Curious as a person and I always eager for new challenges and opportunities to learn and grow from. I have always enjoyed working both independently and in teams with talented people from all over the world.
Programming languages C# (.NET 3+ / ASP NET / Xamarin) Python TypeScript/JavaScript F# Swift Java C/C++ I have dappled around with several other languages, and always find it interesting to see how different tools try to solve problems.</description></item></channel></rss>